Hello friends,
welcome to Insights. Today we are going to talk about
whenever we have to go to
hospital for treatment of any of our diseases,
then we
use the health policy that we have and the
process that happens with the hospital is
called process [ __ ] cashless process.
Sometimes cashless is not available, so the second
process is of reversal, so
during this process there is an approval, not one but
two types of initial approval.
Today we are going to talk about initial approval,
this is called initial approval,
when we are admitted in a hospital for
treatment of any disease,
so today in this video we are going to discuss this in detail,
so let's start the video.
[Music]
Whenever we go to a hospital for treatment of our disease,
we definitely need our health card. The
health card can be
processed only with the hospital.
We can never process it on our own.
Doing it on our own means that
when we have to get treatment for any disease,
we have to go to the hospital and the
insurance company of the hospital.
After getting admitted in the hospital, there are two types
of treatment.  We get cashless
reimbursement,
I have already
told you about cashless and investment, but let me
tell you about cashless, our card is accepted in the hospital,
if that hospital is
in the panel with the insurance company, then
we will get cashless there, if that
hospital is not in the panel
with the insurance company, then if we
have the card of the insurance company, then we will have to reverse
our final bill etc., we will have to reverse it,
after sending it to the insurance company,
so today we are going to talk about when we are
admitted for cashless, that is, when the
approval comes in the hospital, the
initial process is taken, it is called initial approval,
so what is its process, its
process is this, when we are
admitted in a hospital, there is a TP team, just
like there is a reception, similarly there is a
TP desk, we
go there and see how the cashless
process is done there, there we have to
check our health card whether it
is in our panel or not, after that
when we go to the hospital team, we get
free authorization from us  We sign the form,
after signing it, they take our ID and a
photocopy of the card.
After doing all this, they file the form, then
they fill it or meet the doctor, whatever
treatment we are giving, whatever is the history of the patient, whatever
problem he has, that is filled in.
After filling the form with the doctor, some details
of the patient are entered like policy number
or any other ID number, his card
number etc., whatever it is, it is entered in
front, his gender is entered, whatever it is, it is
filed in the form,
after that an estimate is entered for it, if the
patient is admitted for 3 days, then the
hospital will charge this much for the room, this much for the
medicine, this much for the live tests, that is an estimate,
an idea of ​​the estimate, it is made in it and the
total amount is sent, then it will
support, if you send an estimate of ₹20000
for three days, then the
insurance company will definitely not accept ₹20000 from it.
What happens in it is that the insurance
company checks the documents and if they
feel that the patient needs to be admitted, he needs
treatment, then it
gives initial approval and
gives him time of Rs. 12000-13000 out of Rs. 20000, so that is
not a final amount, that is the initial Apollo,
I will show you a letter of Raksha
company, of Raksha TV, what is there in it, that there is
a letter of initial approval, so in it the
details of the patient's diagnosis etc., all the things about the hospital are
mentioned in it, so I will show you on the computer
screen
what type of initial approval letter is there, so let's see
this is the cashless authorization letter of Raxaul TV,
see in it it is written that this is the name of the company,
okay, in this it is a cashless
letter, what is there after this, there is a
claim number here, I have
removed this claim number from here, it is someone else's letter,
so I cannot show it on the screen,
after this this sex  Here the
name of the hospital is written, this is the field
here the name of the insurance company is written,
Insurance Company Limited,
in the patient here there is a number from the send camp,
it has a period, from when to
when is the policy valid, what happens on this, the
TP team had written it on it that the
admission has happened on this date, its time is also mentioned here,
it comes mentioned here, for example, let's say
today is the 28th, so it is the 28th,
so what happens in this is that we will
write 28 here, its time will
come and in it we enter the expected date, in the initial
approval form, in the authorization
form, we enter the expected date till
when the patient can be admitted, so in it the
same data which we enter,
its room category is there,
where the patient is admitted, the
estimate is written, so in it I will
show in a video about diagnosis, how India goes, in it there is a
diagnosis,
in it the history of the patient, the
problem, insurance  Whatever
problem he is having, then that provisional initial
diagnosis that he is having this problem,
this diagnosis will be made by the doctor only, it is
written here,
then the treatment is written in it that
this type of management is surgical, it is
medical
management, surgical is
related to some surgery and medical is in it
normally medicine etc. is given or otherwise there is no
type of surgery, some
transplant etc. has to be done, that is
called medical management, from the
estimate which the hospital sends,
send it to the insurance company, the hospital made an estimate of 18000 and
sent it here,
and in this they have made a deduction of 2000,
some payment is zero, the deduction is zero,
16000 rupees means the hospital had
sent an approval of 18000, sent it for initial approval, it was the
estimated amount, from that
they have passed 16000, this is
not a final approval, this is the initial approval,
when the insurance company
Sir, she checks the documents,
verifies some documents,
investigates them and then the role that she gives is
called initial approval and
when the patient completes the treatment,
after that at the
time of discharge the
insurance company sends him the bill again, I am going to show
in the second video
what type of final approvals come and how that
final approval looks, is there any
deduction in it, I am going to bring it in the next video, that's all
in this video, I
hope you liked the video, see you
in the next video in which we will
talk about the final football match, if you guys
are new to the channel then subscribe to the channel,
like the video
and share this video with your friends, the
channel should definitely get likes
because the mother makes a video only
when you want likes and comments, then
subscribe to the channel as well, see you
in the next video, till then thank you
so much